Guide to the Bernard F. Burgunder Collection of George Bernard Shaw, [ca. 1810]-1990.
Bernard F. Burgunder Collection of George Bernard Shaw, [ca. 1810]-1990.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Bernard F. Burgunder Collection of George Bernard Shaw, [ca. 1810]-1990.
4617
Bernard, Shaw 1856-1950.
53.8 linear ft.
Manuscripts, letters, documents, photographs, broadsides, microfilms, videocassettes, audio cassettes, posters, and other materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Manuscripts, letters, documents, photographs, broadsides, microfilms, videocassettes, audio cassettes, posters, and other materials by and about Shaw, covering all aspects of his varied literary, critical, personal, and political activities.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
British playwright; literary, art, and music critic; lecturer and essayist; and socialist. One of the founders of the Fabian Society, precursor of England's Socialist Party.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Manuscripts, letters, documents, photographs, broadsides, microfilms, videocassettes, audio cassettes, posters, and other materials by and about Shaw, covering all aspects of his varied literary, critical, personal, and political activities. Includes 2122 manuscripts by or about Shaw; 832 letters by Shaw; 2580 photographs, including some 2400 of productions of Shaw's plays at the Arts Theatre Club in London, 70 photographs of Shaw himself and 14 taken by Shaw; and a large collection of theater programs for productions of Shaw's plays through 1990, reviews of his plays, newspaper clippings which include articles on his many speeches and lectures, and proofs and rehearsal copies of his plays. Also, recordings of some of Shaw's radio broadcasts, and a 1962 BBC broadcast of Blanche Patch remembering Shaw. Also included are a bronze cast of a bust of Shaw by Clare Winsten, 1946, together with a letter from Shaw to her husband Stephen suggesting her as the artist for the bust (June 13, 1946), and related photographs, letters, and other materials concerning the bust's appearance at the opening of the St. Pancras Library and Shaw Theatre in 1971.
Correspondents include: Mrs. Patrick Campbell, the British Broadcasting Corporation, Lady Gregory, Hesketh Pearson, Blanche Patch, Charlotte Payne-Townshend Shaw (his wife), Harley Granville-Barker, Henry Arthur Jones, Gertrude Lawrence, F.E. Loewenstein, Sean O'Casey, Dame Sybil Thorndike, George Herbert Thring, Gene Tunney, H.G. Wells, Dan H. Laurence, and Bernard F. Burgunder. Also included are a 1903 letter to Charles Dickens's daughter Kate Perugini, concerning her father's literary stature, and an 1889 letter to Tighe Hopkins in which Shaw predicts the future of his own writing career.
Additional materials relating to Ann Elder Jackson. Includes autograph letters, notes and postcards from George Bernard Shaw to Ms. Jackson. Subjects include travel plans, rehearsal schedules, and diary engagements in addition to detailed instructions for Elder as his secretary.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Shaw, Bernard,1856-1950.; Burgunder, Bernard.; Campbell, Patrick, Mrs., 1865-1940.; Dickens, Charles, 1812-1870.; Granville-Barker, Harley, 1877-1946.; Gregory, 1852-1932.; Halls, Robert James, 1873-1932.; Hopkins, Tighe, 1856-1919.; Jones, Henry Arthur, 1851-1929.; Laurence, Dan H.; Lawrence, Gertrude.; Loewenstein, Fritz Erwin, 1901-; O'Casey, Sean, 1880-1964.; Patch, Blanche, b. 1878.; Pearson, Hesketh, 1887-1964.; Perugini, Kate, 1839-1929.; Shaw, Charlotte Frances Payne-Townshend.; Thorndike, Sybil, 1882-1976.; Thring, George Herbert, 1859-1941.; Tunney, Gene, 1898-; Wells, H. G.(Herbert George), 1866-1946.; Winsten, Clare, 1894-1989.; Arts Theatre Club (London, England).; St. Pancras Library.; British Broadcasting Corporation.
Subjects:
Drama--England--History--Sources.; Theater--England--History--20th century.; English literature--20th century.; Modernism (Literature).; Irish literature.; Socialism--Great Britain--History--Sources.; Musical criticism--England.; Art criticism--England.; English literature--History and criticism.; Socialism and theater.; Authors and the theater.; Theater--Production and direction.; Theatrical posters.; Authors, English.; Authors, Irish.; Authors, English.
Places:
Great Britain--Politics and government--20th century.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Portraits.; Busts (figures).
INFORMATION FOR USERS
The published guide, containing more information about the collection, is available by clicking here. 6 MB PDF
RELATED MATERIALS
A large collection of books by and about Shaw (ca. 2530 titles) is also housed in the repository.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Manuscripts
Box 1-7
A - Ad
The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God
An - B
C - F
Diaries
G - I
J - P
Q - Z
Series II. Documents
Box 8
Series III. Envelopes annotated by Shaw
Box 9
Series IV. Outgoing Correspondence
Box 10-18, 112-114
Undated-1907
1908-1915
1916-1920
1921-1930
Dodd, Meade, & Co.
1931-1937
1938-1943
1944-1950
E. M. Wheeler
Ann Elder [Jackson]
Series V. Manuscripts and Correspondence to and by others
Boxes 19-32, 115-116
A - B
Campbell
Campbell 1939 - D
Cockerell, Sir Sydney To Judy Musters
E - K
Healy, George H. To Bernard F. Burgunder
L - Pas
Laurence, Dan H.
Mushlin, M. Harry to Bernard F. Burgunder
Musters, Judy to Ann Carr Jackson
Patterson, Jane
Pat - Shav
Shaw - Sz
T - Z
Watt, W. P.
Series VI. Miscellaneous Printed Material
Boxes 33-37
A - H
Collected Letters
I - S
T - Z, and letters
Works - Reviews, etc.
Series VII. Reviews on G.B. Shaw
Boxes 38-39
Series VIII. Miscellaneous Printed Material by others
Boxes 40-42, 44-48
A - C
D - I
J - L
M - Pa
Pb - R
S - Shaw Festival
Shaw Society - Z
Series IX. Statuettes
Boxes 43
Series X. Photographs of Shaw and Others
Boxes 49-53
Photographs of Shaw
A - F
G - M
N - Z
Series XI. Photographs of Shaw's plays
Boxes 54-56
A - C
D - O
P - Z
Series XII. Shaviana
Boxes 57-64
General Shaviana
Shaviana Hat
Printed Shaviana
A - Shaw (F)
Shaw (G - Z)
Laing Collection Clippings
Series XIII. Playbills, Posters, Pressbooks
Boxes 65 and Mapcase Folders
Series XIV. Theater Programs
Boxes 66-73
A - B
C
D - G
H - Maj
Mak - Mz)
O - Sa
Sb - Z
Miscellaneous
Series XV. Arts Theatre Club Photographs
Boxes 74-96, 111-111B
Arts Theatre Club Photographs (8x10)
Unidentified, A
B
Ca - Cn
Co - Cz
D
E
F
G
Ha - Hob
Hoc - Hz
I
J - L
Maa - Mas
Mat - Mz
N - O
P - Q
R
Sa - Sh
Si - Sz
Ta - Tra
Trb - Tz
U - V
W - Z
Arts Theatre Club Photographs (8x14)
Unidentified, A - B
C - G
H - J
K - L
M - N
O - R
S
T
U - Z
Arts Theatre Club Photographs (11x17)
A - C
D - G
H - L
M - Q
R - S
T - Z
Arts Theatre Club Photographs (oversized)
Series XVI. Miscellany Media
Boxes 117-120
Series XVII. Museum items
Boxes 122, 124 and MU items
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I Manuscripts
  - A - Ad
    - GBS: Autograph Manuscript [fragment] "actually claims to be the first playwright to put sexual love on the stage,...", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      See: Harris, Frank. Bernard Shaw. New York, 1931. p. 233.; with transcript
    - GBS: Address Book, [pre-1900]; photostat; 133 leaves (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Made from the Microfilm of the address book in the British Museum, numbered 50715
    - GBS: Autograph Manuscript: Address Book, ca. 1902; photostat; 55 leaves (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - GBS: Typed Manuscript Signed: Address to the U.S.A. [fragment], Summer 1940; 1 leaf (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Includes note by GBS dated April 7, 1942; See: p. 322 of R. Mander & J. Mithcenson, Theatrical Companion to Shaw (London 1954) for text and circumstances
    - GBS: Typed Manuscript: Address to the U.S.A., Summer 1940; copy; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 5)
      From the Tunney Collection
  - The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God
    - Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God, illustration proofs; 151 items
      Made from various states of the wood engravings prepared by John Farleigh for the book published in December 1932; all items formed part of the Black Girl Collection, acquired by Cornell in October 1984
      - GBS: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration proofs] 1) Title page, n.d.; 3 proofs; 3 leaves (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - GBS: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration proofs] 2) Headpiece with capital W, n.d.; 3 proofs; 2 leaves (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - GBS: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration proofs] 3) Lord of Hosts, n.d.; 4 proofs; 4 leaves (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - GBS: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration proofs] 4) God of Job, n.d.; 4 proofs; 4 leaves (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - GBS: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration proofs] 5) Ecclesiastes, n.d.; 8 proofs; 4 leaves (Box 1, Folder 10)
        3 leaves mounted together on stationery of M.H. Mushlin
      - GBS: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration proofs] 6) King Richard the Lion, n.d.; 7 proofs; 5 leaves (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - GBS: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration proofs] 7) Micah, n.d.; 3 proofs; 2 leaves (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - GBS: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration proofs] 8) Myopic professor, n.d.; 9 proofs; 8 leaves (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - GBS: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration proofs] 9) Roman soldier, n.d.; 12 proofs; 8 leaves (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - GBS: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration proofs] 10) Conjuror, n.d.; 12 proofs; 8 leaves (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - GBS: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration proofs] 11) Ancient fisherman, n.d.; 12 proofs; 6 leaves (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - GBS: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration proofs] 12) Explorers, n.d.; 9 proofs; 5 leaves (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - GBS: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration proofs] 13) Sculptor, n.d.; 16 proofs; 11 leaves (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - GBS: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration proofs] 14) Arab, n.d.; 7 proofs; 4 leaves (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - GBS: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration proofs] 15) Voltaire, n.d.; 8 proofs; 7 leaves (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - GBS: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration proofs] 16) Irishman, n.d.; 10 proofs; 6 leaves (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - GBS: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration proofs] 17) Too busy to search, n.d.; 8 proofs; 6 leaves (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - GBS: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration proofs] 18) Headpiece of typewriter and books, 5 proofs; 3 leaves (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - GBS: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration proofs] 19) Peace, n.d.; 1 proof; 1 leaf (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - GBS: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration proofs] 20) Tailpiece of spear and harp, 2 proofs; 2 leaves (Box 1, Folder 25)
        (See also #21)
      - GBS: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration proofs] 21) Endpapers, 2 proofs; 6 leaves (Box 1, Folder 26)
        One proof used for trial layout of front and back covers of the book; also contains proof of Tailpiece of spear and harp
      - GBS: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration proofs] 22) Back cover design, n.d.; 2 proofs; 2 leaves (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God, illustration sketches; pencil, ink, and watercolor; 40 items (Box 1, Folder 28-67)
      Preparatory sketches, for the book published in December 1932; all items formed part of the Black Girl Collection, acquired by Cornell in October 1984
      - Farleigh: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 1) Title page, June 15, 1932; pencil; (Box 1, Folder 28)
        On verso is written Shaw's autographed letter signed to Farleigh
      - GBS: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 2) Title page, n.d.; pencil (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - Farleigh: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 3) Title page, n.d.; watercolor (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - Farleigh: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 4) Headpiece with capital W, n.d.; watercolor (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Farleigh: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 5) Lord of Hosts, n.d.; watercolor (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - Farleigh: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 6) God of Job, n.d.; watercolor (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - GBS: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 7) Ecclesiastes, n.d.; pencil (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - Farleigh: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 8) Ecclesiastes, n.d.; watercolor (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - Farleigh: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 9) King Richard the Lion, n.d.; watercolor (Box 1, Folder 36)
      - GBS: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 10) Micah, n.d.; watercolor (Box 1, Folder 37)
        Also contains a note in Shaw's hand on verso
      - Farleigh: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 11) Micah, October 30, 1932; watercolor (Box 1, Folder 38)
        With a hinged overlay; on verso is Shaw's autographed letter signed to Farleigh
      - Farleigh: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 12) Micah, n.d.; pencil tracing (Box 1, Folder 39)
        With note on verso by Shaw; (see also #34)
      - Farleigh: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 13) Micah, n.d.; watercolor (Box 1, Folder 40)
      - GBS: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 14) Myopic professor, n.d.; watercolor (Box 1, Folder 41)
      - Farleigh: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 15) Myopic professor, n.d.; watercolor (Box 1, Folder 42)
      - GBS: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 16) Beanstalk, n.d.; ink (Box 1, Folder 43)
        Drawn on verso of printed proof sheet, numbered 64, and including the heading "Thou Art The Man," for the "Preface on Doctors" to Shaw's play The Doctor's Dilemma.
      - GBS: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 17) Roman soldier as Bobadil, n.d.; ink (Box 1, Folder 44)
      - GBS: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 18) Roman soldier as Tin Wellington, n.d.; ink (Box 1, Folder 45)
      - Farleigh: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 19) Roman soldier, 1st version, n.d.; watercolor (Box 1, Folder 46)
      - Farleigh: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 20) Roman soldier, 2nd version, watercolor (Box 1, Folder 47)
      - GBS: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 21) Conjuror, on Malvern Hotel stationery, n.d.; pencil (Box 1, Folder 48)
      - GBS: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 22) Conjuror, on plain stationery, n.d.; pencil (Box 1, Folder 49)
      - Farleigh: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 23) Conjuror, n.d.; watercolor (Box 1, Folder 50)
      - Farleigh: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 24) Ancient fisherman, n.d.; watercolor (Box 1, Folder 51)
      - Farleigh: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 25) Explorers, n.d.; watercolor (Box 1, Folder 52)
      - Farleigh: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 26) Sculptor, n.d.; watercolor (Box 1, Folder 53)
      - Farleigh: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 27) Arab, n.d.; watercolor (Box 1, Folder 54)
      - Farleigh: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 28) Voltaire, n.d.; watercolor (Box 1, Folder 55)
      - GBS: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 29) Irishman, n.d.; watercolor (Box 1, Folder 56)
        With draft of Shaw's autographed manuscript; colophon note written on verso
      - Farleigh: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 30) Irishman, 1st version, n.d.; watercolor (Box 1, Folder 57)
      - Farleigh: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 31) Irishman, 2nd version, watercolor (Box 1, Folder 58)
      - Farleigh: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 32) Too busy to search, n.d.; watercolor (Box 1, Folder 59)
      - GBS: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 33) Headpiece of typewriter and books, watercolor (Box 1, Folder 60)
      - Farleigh: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 34) Headpiece of typewriter and books, pencil (Box 1, Folder 61)
        With note by Shaw; drafts for Micah on verso
      - Farleigh: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 35) Headpiece of typewriter and books, watercolor (Box 1, Folder 62)
      - GBS: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 36) Peace, n.d.; watercolor (Box 1, Folder 63)
        With note by Shaw
      - Farleigh: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 37) Peace, n.d.; pencil (Box 1, Folder 64)
      - Farleigh: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 38) Tailpiece of spear and harp, watercolor (Box 1, Folder 65)
      - Farleigh: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 39) Endpaper design, single unit, watercolor (Box 1, Folder 66)
      - Farleigh: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [Illustration sketches] 40) Cover design, n.d.; watercolor (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - GBS: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [proof sheets], October 10, 1933; photocopy; 5 leaves (Box 1, Folder 68)
      Made from Photostats of originals in National Library of Scotland; showing autograph revisions by Shaw
    - GBS: Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in Her Search For God [pre-proof] Title page, 1932; 12 leaves (Box 1, Folder 69)
      Trial layouts for title and imprint, including beginning of text, and proof of the Sculptor engraving; formed part of the Black Girl Collection; ink notes on 2 proofs by John Farleigh
    - GBS: Typed Manuscript: The Adventures of the Black Girl in her Search for God [stage version], September 1968; copy; 91 leaves +1 item (Box 2, Folder 1)
      "Adapted for the stage by Christopher Isherwood;" with a copy of the printed program of the first and only production of this version (Mark Taper Forum, 1968); gifts of Gordon Davidson
  - An-B
    - GBS: Typed Manuscript: Anecdote of an incident which took place on the opening night of On the Rocks, typescript; 1 leaf (Box 2, Folder 2)
      With holograph additions and notes by Shaw
    - GBS: Autograph Manuscript: "after Flaxman" [& drawing], Manuscript; transcript; and copy; 1 leaf + 2 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Probably Shaw was caricaturing John (1755-1826) Flaxman's drafting style, parodying "The Pilgrim of Love" by Flaxman, or making facetious comparison with his own draughtsmanship
    - GBS: American Patriots and Persecutions: A Letter by G. Bernard Shaw, July 1919; photocopy; 3 leaves + 2 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      On acid-free paper; made from original article printed on p. 388 of Vol. 41, No. 9 of Pearson's Magazine; with a copy of p. 386 on which is printed a paragraph by Shaw about Woodrow Wilson, from a letter to Frank Harris. See: Pearson's Magazine for the original
    - GBS: Typed Manuscript: Androcles and the Lion, ca. 1950?; Carbon copy; interleaved in paper binder; 49 leaves (Box 2, Folder 5)
      Date unknown; with some stage directions in margins, mostly in pencil
    - GBS: Autograph Manuscript: Annajanska, January 9-10, 1918; 3 leaves + copies (Box 2, Folder 6)
      Rehearsal notes; produced at the Coliseum, January 21, 1918; copy included
    - GBS: Autograph Manuscript Signed: Answers to interview questions, August 27, 1945; ink; 2 leaves (Box 2, Folder 7)
      In red ink, "Exclusive to Miss Dorothy Royal" to two typed questions; one on the capabilities of the Labour Government, the other on prospects for polygamy in postwar Europe
    - GBS: Autograph Manuscript: Answers to questions on divorce, 1920?; 3 leaves (Box 2, Folder 8)
      Three typed questions with Shaw's holograph answers
    - GBS: Autograph Manuscript: Arms and the Man; Great Catherine; You Never Can Tell, 24 leaves + copies (Box 2, Folder 9)
      Rehearsal notes for the productions of Arms and the Man (December 11, 1919); Great Catherine (February 17, 1921); You Never Can Tell (November 19, 1920)
    - GBS: Designs for men's costumes for Arms and the Man, 5 leaves (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - GBS: Typed Manuscript: Arms and the Man & The Chocolate Soldier, 1927-28; 1 leaf + 2 + 1 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      Also contains photocopy of another typing of the same statement, dated "April 1926;" including handwritten notes by Blanche Patch and Dan H. Laurence; explanatory note added on separate leaf by Bernard F. Burgunder
    - GBS: Typed Manuscript: Arms and the Man & The Chocolate Soldier (2), 1927; 2 leaves + abbreviated typed transcript of 1 leaf (Box 2, Folder 12)
      A statement concerning the relationship between Shaw's Arms and the Man and Oscar Strauss's The Chocolate Soldier (original-Der Tapfere Soldat)
    - GBS: Autograph Manuscript: Augustus Does His Bit, January 22, 1917; 8 leaves + copies (Box 2, Folder 13)
      Rehearsal notes; various dates, in Shaw's hand, appear on the manuscript
    - GBS: Typed Manuscript Signed: "Authentic Shavian Democracy", 4 leaves + 1 + 1 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      Article appeared in Time and Tide of February 10, 1945; later reprinted in Time and Tide Anthology in 1956; note by Bernard Burgunder included
    - GBS: Manuscript Signed: Autograph, n.d.; 1 leaf (Box 2, Folder 15)
      Corner of a document cut off to show only Shaw's signature; in envelope
    - GBS: Typed Manuscript: Draft scheme of Autumn Lectures by GBS, n.d.; copy?; 7 leaves (Box 2, Folder 16)
      Lists a series of topics for thirteen lectures, and possible speakers
    - GBS: Back to Methuselah [Preface][proof A], 1938?; printed; 1 leaf (Box 2, Folder 17)